A Finding Aid to the Erwin Panofsky Papers, 1904-1990 (bulk dates 1920-1968), in the Archives of American Art
Archives of American Art
- Correspondence, 1921-1978, undated; Series 1; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 1-16; 16 linear ft. Reels 2108-2128)
  - Libraries, 1941-1967; 1.4; Archival Resource Key
    - United States, Archival Resource Key (Box 14)
      - United States, Texas (Library of the University of Texas, Austin), 1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 62)
      - United States, Wisconsin (Ripon College Library), 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 63)
  - Colleges, Universities, and Institutes, 1936-1968, and undated; 1.5; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence is available on reels 2126-2127.
    - A-Z, General (single letters, Albany, State University of New York - Wooster, College of), 1941-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 14, Folder 64-65)
      Albany, State University of New York at
      Archaeological Institute of America
      University of Arkansas
      University of Auckland
      Bauerische Akademie der Wissenschaftsgeschichte
      Bennett College
      Boston College
      Boston University
      Bowling Green State University
      Brandeis University
      Université de Bruxelles
      Colgate University
      Dalhousie University
      Denison University
      Drew University
      Ellis Island for Higher Education, Inc.
      Emma Willard School
      Emory University
      Freiburg, Albert Ludwigs Universitat
      Frieburg, Die Kunstwissenschaftliche Gesellschaft
      University of Hawaii
      Indiana University
      Karel van Mander Kunsthistorische Instituut
      Louisiana State University
      University of Louisville
      Universität Marburg
      Massachusetts Institute of Technology
      University of Nebraska
      New School
      University of North Carolina
      University of North Dakota
      Nova Scotia Technical College
      Ohio Wesleyan University
      University of Oklahoma
      Universita di Pavia
      Philadelphia College of Art
      Pomona College
      Reed College
      University of Rhode Island
      Rockford College
      Rockefeller Institute
      Rollins College
      Royal Swedish Academy of Letters, History and Antiquities
      Saint Meinrad Seminary
      State University College on Long Island
      Temple University
      University of Texas
      University of Toronto
      Washington University
      Wayne State University
      Weil Institute
      Western Michigan University
      Western Reserve University
      Wilson College
      College of Wooster
    - Académie Royal de Belgique - Bard College, 1950-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Academie Royal de Belgique
      American Academy in Rome
      Amherst College
      Bard College
    - Bowdoin, College, 1953-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 2)
    - Brown University, 1946-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Bryn Mawr College, 1937-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 4)
    - University of Buffalo - University of California, Los Angeles, 1939-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 5)
    - Carleton College - Carnegie Institute of Technology, 1951-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Center for the Study of Democratic Institutions, 1960-1961, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - University of Chicago - Colby College - University of Colorado, 1944-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Columbia University, 1952-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Connecticut College - Courtauld Institute of Art, 1941-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 10)
      Connecticut College
      Cooper Union
      Cornell University
      Courtauld Institute of Art
    - Dartmouth College - University of Delaware, 1940-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Duke University - Florida State University - Goucher College, 1948-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Harvard University, 1936-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 13-14)
    - Haverford College - Hobart and William Smith Colleges, 1954-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - University of Houston - University of Illinois, 1942-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Institute for Advanced Study, 1939-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - Institute of International Education - State University of Iowa - Jewish Theological Seminary, 1939-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Johns Hopkins University, 1946-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - University of Kansas - Lowell Institute, 1948-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 20)
      University of Kansas
      University of Kentucky
      Kenyon College
      University of London
      Lowell Institute
    - Manhattanville College of the Sacred Heart - Middlebury College, 1946-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 21)
      Manhattanville College of the Sacred Heart
      Michigan State College
      University of Michigan
      Middlebury College
    - University of Minnesota - Mount Holyoke College - University of New Hampshire, 1949-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - New York University, 1945-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - New York University, Institute of Fine Arts, 1937-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 24-25)
    - Northwestern University - University of Notre Dame - Oberlin College, 1937-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Ohio State University, 1952-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - University of Oregon - Oxford University - Pennsylvania State University, 1954-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - University of Pennsylvania, 1946-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - University of Pittsburgh, 1959-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Princeton University (general), 1938-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Princeton University, Department of Art and Archaeology, 1940-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Richmond Area University Center, Inc. - University of Rochester, 1947-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Rutgers University, 1946-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - St. John's College, Annapolis - Skidmore College, 1945-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 35)
      St. John's College, Annapolis
      St. John's University, Minnesota
      Sarah Lawrence College
      Skidmore College
    - Smith College, 1951-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 36)
    - University of Southern California - Uppsala University, 1952-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 37)
      University of Southern California
      Swarthmore College
      Syracuse University
      Uppsala University (original letters filed under Paulsson, Gregor)
    - Vassar College, 1938-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 38)
    - University of Virginia, 1941-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 39)
    - Warburg Institute, 1948-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 40)
    - University of Washington - Wellesley College, 1947-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 15, Folder 41)
    - Wells College - Wesleyan University - Wheaton College, 1949-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Williams College, circa 1954-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 2)
    - University of Wisconsin, 1954-1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 3)
    - Yale University, 1955-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Organizations, Societies, and Congresses, 1937-1967; 1.6; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence is available on reels 2127.
    - Académie Royale de Belgique - American Numismatic Society, 1956-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 5)
      Académie Royale de Belgique
      American Academy of Arts and Letters
      American Academy of Arts and Sciences
      American Council of Learned Societies
      American Numismatic Society
    - American Philosophical Society, 1955-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Amsterdam XVIIth International Congress - Brussels Ministère de l'Education, 1953-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 7)
      Amsterdam XVIIth International Congress of the History of Art
      Belgian American Educational Foundation, Inc.
      Brussels Ministère de l'Education Nationale et de la Culture
    - College Art Association, 1940-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
    - College English Association - Medieval Academy of America, 1948-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 10)
      College English Association, Committee for the Study of Mankind
      Colloquia Humanitas Conimbrigensia, Coimbra, Portugal
      Experimental Program in Teacher Education, Temple University
      Gottesman Foundation (copies; originals filed under Gottesman, D. S.)
      John Simon Guggenheim Memorial Foundation
      Hispanic Society of America
      Samuel H. Kress Foundation
      Medieval Academy of America
    - Midwestern College Art Conference - United States National Student Association, 1937-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 11)
      Midwestern College Art Conference
      National Council of Churches of Christ in the U.S.A., Department of Worship and the Arts
      New York Renaissance Club
      Phi Beta Kappa
      Renaissance Society of America
      Royal Society of Arts, London
      Society for the Protection of Science and Learning
      United States National Student Association
    - John Hay Whitney Foundation - YMHA, New York, 1950-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Periodicals, 1937-1967; 1.7; Archival Resource Key
    - America Illustrated - American Scholar, 1959-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Art Bulletin - Arte Antica e Moderna, 1938-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 14)
      Art Bulletin, 1938-1967
      Art in America, 1955-1965
      Art News, 1957-1961
      Art Quarterly, 1952
      L'Arte, 1965-1966
      Arte Antica e Moderna, 1961
    - Art Digest - Bulletin of the Atomic Scientists, 1952-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 15)
    - Burlington Magazine - Diogène, 1937-1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 16)
      Burlington Magazine
      College Art Journal
      Cinnaissance des Arts
      Daedalus
      Diogène
    - Gazette des Beaux-Arts (see also: Adhémar, Jean), 1948-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Isis, 1955-1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Journal of Aesthetics and Art Criticism - Pageant, 1939-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 19)
      Journal of Aesthetics and Art Criticism
      Journal of the Warburg and Courtauld Institutes
      Library Chronicle
      Magazine of Art
      Marsyas
      Master Drawings
      New York Times Book Review
      Pageant
    - Phoebus - University Magazine, 1946-1964; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 20)
      Phoebus
      Phoenix
      Progress of Medieval and Renaissance Studies
      Revista de Occidente
      University Magazine (Princeton)
  - Miscellaneous, 1940-1969; 1.8; Archival Resource Key
    Correspondence is available on reels 2127-2128.
    - Acknowledgements, Early Netherlandish Painting, 1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 21)
    - Book Dealers, Antiquarians, etc., 1949-1954; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 22)
    - Homage Issue of Bulletin des Musée Royaux - Thank You Letters, 1955; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 23)
    - Embassies and Consulates, 1961-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 24)
    - Festchrift Acknowledgements, 1961; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - H. P. Kraus Old and Rare Books, Manuscripts, Maps, 1955-1965; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - Photo Resources, 1951-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Seventieth Birthday, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - U. S. Government, 1954-1966; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Review Requests (various publishers), 1949-1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 30-31)
    - Requests for Contributions to Encyclopedias, Dictionaries, and Lexicons, 1940-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 32)
    - Requests to Write Books, 1953-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 33)
  - Unfilmed Correspondence, 1925-1967, undated; 1.9; Archival Resource Key
    - Correspondence, 1925-1967, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 16, Folder 34-37)
- Writings, 1915-1968, undated; Series 2; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 17-19; 2.3 linear ft.)
  Writings by Panofsky consist of drafts, notes, and manuscripts of articles, book reviews, books, and lectures. The early writings are in German.
  This series is arranged by format.
  - Articles, Archival Resource Key (Box 17)
    - "Artist, Scientist, Genius," ( The Renaissance: Six Essays, Metropolitan Museum of Art, 1952), Archival Resource Key (Box 17)
      - Drafts and Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 1)
      - Revised Version, 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - "Canopus Deus," ( Gazette des Beaux Arts, LVI, 1961), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - "Comments on Art and Reformation," (American Historical Association, 1960; Symbols of Transformation, The Art Museum, Princeton University, 1968; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 4)
    - "Dürer's Last Picture," ( Burlington Magazine, March 1943), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 5)
    - "Erasmus and the Visual Arts" ( Journal of the Warburg and Courtauld Institutes, XXXII, 1969), Archival Resource Key (Box 17)
      - Drafts, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 6-7)
      - Manuscript, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 8)
      - Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 9)
    - "Frank Aydelotte as Director of the Institute for advanced Study," [obituary] ( Swarthmore College Bulletin, LIV, 5, 1957), circa 1956-1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 10)
    - "Giotto and Maimonides in Avignon," ( Journal of the Walters Art Gallery, IV, 1941), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - "Good Government or Fortune?: The Iconography of a Newly-Discovered Composition by Rubens," ( Gazette des Beaux Arts, LXVIII, 1966; lecture version, Harvard and Stockholm, 1966), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - "John Hey's Ecce Homo: Some Speculations about Its Author, Its Donor, and Its Iconography" (Brussels, Musée Royal des Beaux-Arts, Bulletin, v, 1956, pp. 95-132), Archival Resource Key (Box 17)
      - Corrected Draft, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 13)
      - Manuscript, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 14)
      - Research Notes and Correspondence, 1955-1956, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - "The Ideological Antecedents of the Rolls-Royce Radiator," ( Proceedings of the American Philosophical Society, CVII, 1963), circa 1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - "In Defense of the Ivory Tower," ( Association of Princeton Graduate Alumni, 1953; and revised version presented at 1957 Commencement), circa 1953 and 1957; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - "The Mouse that Michelangelo Failed to Carve" (in: Marsyas. Studies in the History of Art, Supplement 1, Essays in Memory of Karl Lehmann (New York, 1964)), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - "Nebulae in Pariete: Notes on Erasmus' Eulogy on Dürer," ( Journal of the Warurg Institute, 1951), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - "On Movies" ( Princeton University, Department of Art and Archaeology Bulletin, 1939; Rutgers College, 1946; Critique, 1947), circa 1934; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - "Paul Coremans, The Promoter of a New Co-operation between the Natural Sciences and the History of Art," ( Bulletin de l'Institut royal du patrimonie artistique, VIII, 1965, pp. 62-67), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 21)
    - "Postlogium Sugerianum," Art Bulletin, XXIX, 1947, p. 119), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 22)
    - Preface to M. J. Friedländer's Early Netherlandish Painting (1967 edition), circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - "Das Problem des Stils in der Bildenden Kunst,", 1915; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - "Reintegration of a Book of Hours executed in the workshop of the Maître des Grandes Heures de Rohan,'" ( Medieval Studies in the memory of A. Kingsley Porter, 1959), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - "Rembrandt und das Judentum," ( Jahrbuch der Hamburger Kunstsammlungen, XXVIII, 1974), 1920; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - "Sokrates in Hamburg oder von Schönen und Guten," ( Der Querschnitt, XI, no. 9, 1931, pp. 593-599; Gesellschaft5 der Bücherfreunde, 1962), 1951; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 27)
    - " Sol Aequinoctialis Fuit Creatus: Notes on a Composition by Lelio Orsi and Its Possible Connection with the Gregorian Calendar Reform,", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 28)
    - "The Tomby at Arcady at the Fin-de-Siècle," ( Wallraf-Richartz Jahrbuch, XXX, 1968), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 29)
    - "An Unpublished Portrait Drawing by Albrecht Dürer," ( Master Drawings I, 1963), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 30)
    - Book Review, Goldschmidt, Adolph. Die Skulpturen von Freiberg aund Wechselburg, 1924-1925; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 31)
  - Books, Archival Resource Key (Box 17)
    - The Iconography of Correggio's Camera di San Paolo, Archival Resource Key (Box 17)
      - Drafts, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 32-34)
      - Footnotes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 35)
      - Galley Proofs (corrected), 1960; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 36)
      - Illustrations, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 17, Folder 37)
      - Manuscript, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 1)
      - Manuscript (Italian Translation), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 2)
    - Idea: The History of a Concept, Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
      - Appendices, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 3)
      - Footnotes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 4)
      - Manuscript (1968 edition), circa 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 5)
      - Preface (in German), 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - Meaning in the Visual Arts: Papers in and on Art History, Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
      - Preface, List of Illustrations and Captions, Footnotes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 7)
      - Chapter 3, "Abbot Suger and St.-Denis,", circa 1944; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
      - Chapter 4, "Titian's Allegory of Prudence: A Postscript,", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 10)
      - Chapter 5, "The First Page of Giorgio Vasari's Libro, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 11)
      - Chapter 6, "Albrecht Dürer and Classical Antiquity With an Excursus on the Illustrations of Apianus' Inscriptiones in Relation to Dürer,", undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Problems in Titian, Mostly Iconographic (see also: Lecture Notes), Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
      - Draft, undated, Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 13-16)
      - Draft (List of Illustrations), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 17)
      - Galley Proofs (corrected), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 18-19)
      - Manuscript, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 20-27)
      - Notes, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 28)
    - Renaissance and Renascences in Western Art, Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
      - Footnotes and Illustrations (1960 edition), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 29)
    - Saturn and Melancholy: Studies in the History of Natural Philosophy, Religion, and Art [with Raymond Klibansky and Fritz Saxl], Archival Resource Key (Box 18)
      - Galley Proofs (corrected), 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 30)
      - Galley Proofs (corrected), 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 31)
      - Galley Proofs (corrected), 1936; Archival Resource Key (Box 18, Folder 32)
  - Lectures, Archival Resource Key (Box 19)
    - Titian Lectures, New York University Institute of Fine Arts [published as Problems in Titian, Mostly Iconographic] (see also: Books), Archival Resource Key (Box 19)
      - Drafts, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
      - Draft ("Slide Desiderata"), undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 4)
      - Texts, 1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 5-6)
- Biographical Information, 1905-1967; Series 3; Archival Resource Key; (Boxes 19-21; 0.5 linear ft.)
  This series is arranged by record type.
  - Awards and Certificates, 1950-1967; Archival Resource Key; (see also: Box 20) (Box 19, Folder 7)
  - Diplomas (honorary degrees), 1950-1962; Archival Resource Key; (see also: Box 20 and OV 21) (Box 19, Folder 8)
  - Membership Certificates, 1938-1963, undated; Archival Resource Key; (see also: Box 20) (Box 19, Folder 9)
  - Awards and Certificates, 1960-1967; Archival Resource Key; (see also: Box 19) (Box 20, Folder 1)
  - Cylindrical leather case for Rome University diploma, Archival Resource Key (Box 20, Folder 2)
  - Diplomas (doctorate; honorary degrees), 1905-1967; Archival Resource Key; (see also: Box 19 and OV 21) (Box 20, Folder 3)
  - Membership Certificates, 1943-1963; Archival Resource Key; (see also: Box 19) (Box 20, Folder 4)
  - Diplomas (honorary degrees), 1953-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box OV 21)
- Printed Material, 1904-1990, undated; Series 4; Archival Resource Key; (Box 19; 0.5 linear ft.)
  - Articles About/Mentioning Panofsky, 1926-1962; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 10)
  - Books, Bölsche, Wilhelm, Von Sonnen und Sonnenstäubchen, Kosmische Wanderungen; Weinstein, R., Die Philosophischen Grundlagen der Wissenschaften, 1904-1906; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 11)
  - Certificates Presented to Abraham Flexner and Lessing J. Rosenwald (probably composed by Panofsky), 1951-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 12)
  - Clippings, 1941-1967, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 13)
  - Exhibition Catalogs, 1967-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 14)
  - Lecture Announcement, Duke University, 1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 15)
  - Membership List, The British Academy, 1957-1958; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 16)
  - Memorial Program and Tributes, 1968-1969; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous Printed Items Relating to Saturn and Melancholy, 1964-1990; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 18)
  - Programs for Graduation Ceremonies (Panofsky awarded honorary degrees), 1947-1967; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 19)
  - Obituaries (colleagues and friends), 1979-1987; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 20)
  - Reviews of Panofsky's Writings, Archival Resource Key (Box 19)
    - Dürer (all editions), 1943-1959, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Early Netherlandish Painting, 1954-1956; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Gothic Architecture and Scholasticism, 1952-1958, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 23)
    - The Iconography of Corregio's Camera di San Paolo, 1961-1963; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 24)
    - "The Iconography of the Galerie François I at Fontainebleau" [with Dora Panofsky] (Gazette des Beaux Arts, 1958, pp. 113-190), 1959; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 25)
    - Idea, 1952-1960, undated; Archival Resource Key (Box 19, Folder 26)